WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -
I was sifting through Sadoc's old book.
Harfoots must've journeyed
this way a long time ago.
The Istar will surrender to
me, because if he doesn't,
I will slaughter the
halflings he calls friends.
... Túlielde Yallo!
Nori!
Were you headed for the ridgeline?
The survivors will be waiting
for us where we made camp.
- My father, too.
- I think you may have missed them.
- You hoping to find kin as well?
- My betrothed.
If he's even half as strong
as you, I'm certain of it.
I'm not so strong as you think.
Anything you were to me, is ashes now.
So for my part, we don't
ever need to speak again.
D'you really want your horse back?
- You know where he is?
- Meet me here. Tonight.
What are you doin' out
here in the dark, boy?
It's an ambush!
Preparations are nearly
complete, Lord-father.
Must we go to war again?
We'll never truly be safe,
until we've made certain
Sauron is no more.
Since the wearing of this
Ring, I have perceived
glimpses of the unseen world...
Our letters to Celebrimbor
have all gone unanswered.
I fear Sauron may be in Eregion.
The High King has consented to
send me and a small party there,
to ensure Celebrimbor
and his city are safe.
Elrond's task is not
to join your company.
But to lead it.
Still no word from Celebrimbor...
If we take the Axa Bridge,
Eregion is just under 150 leagues.
We shall need an archer, two swordsmen.
I trust you can recommend a set.
Trust? Me?
Are you certain that's wise, commander?
At the High King's urging, I agreed
to appoint you as first lieutenant.
But if you deem that duty beneath
you, I will choose another.
- Yes.
- "Yes" what?
Yes, I can recommend an
archer and two swordsmen.
Who else shall we take
with us, commander?
Lightning?
No earthly force could do this.
This is the work of Sauron.
Camnir. What other paths might we take?
To circumvent it, we shall
either have to turn due north,
adding two weeks to our journey...
Or?
We go south, through the
Hills of Tyrn Gorthad.
Which will get us to
Eregion much faster.
There is evil in those hills.
Ancient, and filled with malice.
Sauron means for us to go
that way. We must go another.
The Enemy is doubtless
watching both roads.
This collapse makes it
more critical than ever
to reach Celebrimbor at speed.
We won't reach anywhere at
speed if we walk into a trap.
We go south.
Commander, I must protest.
Your opinion on the
matter has been heard.
Elrond.
Opinion heard, lieutenant.
We go south.
This company will not take
counsel from that trinket,
nor will you.
If you cannot abide by those terms,
you will leave now and return to Lindon.
- I should like to.
- Then why do you not?
Because I do not wish to see
any of this company slain.
Including you.
Nori!
Nori! Poppy!
Uh...
Um, uh...
Pardon me. I don't suppose you've seen
a pair of halflings come this way?
See you found the goat.
It wasn't... quite what
I was searching for.
Well, there's what you're searchin' for
and there's what you
find, now, isn't there?
Hey dol, merry dol Ring a dong dillow...
Sandflies in the grass
Bees around the willow
There are some stars above your hill.
Stars above most 'ills.
But my friends and I were
looking for these stars.
I had hoped that...
Oh...
My apologies, j-just a moment...
Of sun, stars Moon and mist
Rain and cloudy weather
The branch... of course...
Yes.
It must be.
Poppy!
Get up!
- D'you see him?
- Who?
Who d'you think? Our friend,
the bleedin' Stranger.
Never mind where's he, where are we?
Nori! Run!
I think, I think we lost them.
Where'd you lot come from?
Us?
Where'd you come from?
Oh, my head.
Uh...
- Live here.
- Harfoots live here?
What's an Harfoot?
Well, you are...
Who are you, exactly?
I'm Nobody.
Well, you can't be "Nobody."
Well... That's what everybody calls me.
If everybody calls you Nobody,
doesn't anybody call you somebody?
Well, my mum calls me Merimac.
I'm Poppy.
Hmm.
I'm Nori.
Where'd you get that water from?
- Keep your voice down.
- You stole it, didn't you?
You stole it from that
well. From the big folk.
- But... Where are you going?
- Uh, nowhere.
- Take us with ya.
- Uh, sorry, no outsiders in the village.
Village? What village?
No village! There's no village.
Listen here, Nobody.
Either we're coming with you
or I will turn you in myself
this moment, water-thief.
You're about to meet The
Gund, our dwell-leader.
And if you want her to even
think about takin' you in,
there's four rules.
One, never look her in the eye.
B, always stand three steps back.
Four, don't, ever, ever, no
matter what, call her "The Gund."
- Got it.
Was that three rules or four?
I wasn't really paying attention.
Off you go, have fun now.
Come on. Over there.
That's 'cause it's
had the sunshine on it.
You're there.
Nice, fresh batch, ready to peel.
- Big hat, like mine!
- Like Dad's!
Harfoots, livin' in holes?
It doesn't seem natural.
That's 'cause we're not Harfoots.
We're Stoors.
Stoors?
What were you thinkin',
bringin' 'em here?
Nobody's that stupid.
They needed a place to hide.
What, with half the devils in
the desert searchin' for them?
Boy, if we put your brains in
a vulture, it'd fly backwards.
Be nicer to him.
Are you talkin' back-sass to me?
Oh, that was the fourth rule.
Give me one good reason why I
shouldn't feed you leg, limb, and joint
to those Gaudrim hunting you out there.
Go on, plead your case.
I have walked across
rivers, and mountains,
and deserts to help my
friend find his destiny,
one the fate of the world may
well depend on, yours included...
I said one good reason.
This friend of yours,
who is he, anyways?
- He's a giant.
- A giant?
- What, like an Elf?
- Bigger than that.
So he's a great big Grand-Elf.
He's not an Elf.
He's a wizard.
Well, the only wizard under these skies
is the Dark Wizard.
And the last friend we
need is a friend of his.
Tie 'em up.
What? What? No.
What? Let her go. What Dark Wizard?
The Istar is already much more powerful
than we had anticipated.
He conjured a sandstorm from thin
air that killed two of my men,
He makes his way north now.
Towards... the hermit.
And what of the halflings?
We are scouring the desert even now.
They will not evade us for long.
I swear my life on it.
You are either very foolish, Gaudrim,
or very brave.
Let the Harfoots be your sole concern.
I will see to the Istar myself.
Let him out again.
You should not be wakin'.
Eat earth. Dig deep.
Drink water, hmm?
Go to sleep.
Who... Who are you?
Been awhile since I've been
called much of anythin',
but back in the Withywindle,
folk used to call me Bombadil.
Tom Bombadil.
Down west sinks the sun
Soon you will be gropin'
Don't be bashful now, Goldberry...
When the night-shadows fall
Then the door will open
I've done such as I can
with your filthy robe.
Well, clean your hands, wash your face,
then come join me by the fire.
Is, uh... Is somebody
out there with you?
I thought I heard a woman singing.
Woman? What woman?
Is no one else here with you?
You're here.
That is, I think you are. Are you?
Uh... Yes?
Now, what was it that
you were hopin' to find
under those stars of yours, huh?
Certainly not old Tom.
I was hoping to find my friends.
Shows what stars know, doesn't it?
Newcomers, that's what they are.
One year, it's dark.
The next, you look up,
there's a sea of tiny eyes
lookin' down at ya, a-watching.
Now, they think they know
everythin', but newcomers. Hmm?
Still newcomers.
Wha...
What are you?
Don't you know my name
yet? That's the only answer.
Tell me, who are you,
alone, yourself, and nameless?
But you are young, and I am old.
Eldest, that's what I am.
What do you mean, "Eldest"?
Eldest.
Mark my words, friend,
Tom was there before
the river and the trees.
Tom remembers the first
raindrop and the first acorn.
He knew the dark under the
stars when it was fearless.
This whole place used to be
green. Now, it's all sand.
I had to come see for
myself to believe it.
Even the birdsong
isn't wholly untouched.
Even your tree out
there. Old Man Ironwood.
- I thought it...
- Uh...
He... might be able
to, lend me a branch.
Oh, well you should've tried askin' him.
Easy, Iarwain. Easy.
I know.
This... magic. Can you teach it to me?
Teach you? What's to learn way out 'ere?
You wield power over
trees, over wind and fire.
You wield it, as if it belongs to you.
All things belong each to themselves.
Just as you belong to yourself.
Then, might you teach
me how to wield a staff?
A wizard's staff is like a name.
It's yours to wield already, if
you prove yourself worthy of it.
You showed today that you're not. Yet.
Whether you can become so,
well, we shall soon discover.
I was never meant to find
a staff under these stars.
I was meant to find you. Wasn't I?
What is it?
We're not alone.
Who are they?
Why do they hunt me, and my friends?
You are not the first Istar
who's eaten honey by my fire.
Years ago, there was another.
The Dark Wizard.
What became of him?
Once, he sought to
control magic, like you.
Now, he controls much of Rhûn.
But still, he hungers for more.
You believe his evil will spread?
Not without an ally far more
powerful even than himself.
Sauron.
If these two flames combine into one,
there will be no end to burnin',
till all Middle-earth is ashes.
Can you stop it?
Old Tom's a wanderer, not a warrior.
Great deeds are left to the
hands they were placed in.
And I shall gather lilies,
while yet they grow.
You mean...
You mean my hands.
Is it my task to stop the fire?
Is it my task to face Sauron?
Your task... is to face them both.
I am waiting for you.
What is this place?
Tyrn Gorthad.
Known to Men as the Barrow-downs.
In ancient days, this was where
they laid their lords and kings to rest.
I feel no rest here.
Even the trees seem ill at ease.
Fear not.
Dead Men are no threat.
Keep moving.
Cold be hand and heart and bone
And cold be sleep under stone
For a moment, I thought I heard...
Heard?
What did you hear?
It was almost like a song.
Or the memory of a song.
Galadriel.
Their barding is from Lindon.
The King sent a dispatch
to warn Celebrimbor.
This dispatch?
We must go from this place.
- Daemor!
- Hold on to me.
Don't let go!
Cold old be hand and heart and bone
And cold be sleep under stone
Never more to wake on stony bed
Never, till the Sun
fails and the Moon is dead
In the black wind the stars shall die
Prepare yourselves.
What are they?
Barrow-wights.
Attack!
Still your arrows!
They're impervious to our weapons.
Hold fast. Come with me.
Where are you going?
- Help me open it.
- What?
Hurry!
Lieutenant!
Take it.
- How?
- According to lore,
only the blades with
which they were buried
will return such creatures to rest.
But the Men buried here have been
entombed for over a thousand years.
I think it is safe to say
that something has awoken them.
No.
Someone.
Awakening evil.
Across all of Middle-earth.
Theo! Theo!
- Theo!
Theo!
They left all their weapons.
To a Wildman, an axe-head
is worth more than gold.
Strange, they did not take it with them.
Come, all of you. We move on.
This way. Let's go.
Do not torture yourself, Númenórean.
Theo has survived far worse.
He will weather this.
Theo!
You there. This way.
I say we raid their camps.
We'd be starting a war.
We're already at war, Sea-folk.
What I saw, I do not believe
was done by mortal Men.
They're not Men. They're animals.
They'd eat human flesh if they had to.
Every minute we waste is
another Theo's still out there.
We've got to keep searching.
We could canvass Eastfield Glen.
Whispers are, Wildmen camp there.
That's a good idea.
You'd do better to look north.
Why north?
I've spent weeks searching these
lands, lookin' for loved ones.
That part of the forest is old.
Promise you, there are
Wildmen there, and worse.
You might be right.
Arondir.
Let's not waste any daylight.
Gather water and provisions.
Let's get a move on.
Oh!
There you go.
You missed a spot.
Thanks.
Fancy you never want
for water on your island.
No. In Númenor, we have
water in most of our homes.
I'd like to see that.
I wager your betrothed would too.
We ought to keep moving.
In a moment.
You say you spent time
among the Wildmen, Estrid.
How much?
Uh, I wasn't exactly
among them. I was hidin'.
- Did they ever do you harm?
- Arondir, what are you...
I ask because I noticed
a wound on your neck.
Looks to be recent.
No. That was my fault. I,
um... fell asleep by the fire.
I should've put it out,
but the night was cold.
It was foolish of me.
We all do foolish things sometimes.
Especially in moments of hopelessness.
Estrid, what is this?
Self-burn.
The Wildmen do it to
hide the Mark of Adar.
We would have caught her at the
gate had she not come in with you.
She's a Wildman?
She's one of them.
And she's going to lead
us to all the others.
What was your plan?
Stab me? Take my horse?
Was that it? No?
Then you saw I was a Númenórean.
Had a better idea, didn't you?
You were using me all along.
Wager you don't even have a betrothed.
- Would you rather I died in Mordor?
- I don't know.
Let me think.
What is it?
Be still.
Come quickly.
Theo was not taken by Men at all.
Look.
Well-fed's awake.
Help!
What's out there?
Don't know yet. But whatever
they are, they're big.
Watch your step.
Might be easier to balance
if I had use of my hands.
And easier to escape.
No one could escape in this.
Come on, unlock me.
It's all right.
Be still.
I said it's all right.
Give me your hand.
Help!
Lift me up.
I'm going down.
What was that?
There are nameless things in
the deep places of this world.
This one...
we shall call "supper."
Right, I've conferred
with the village elders.
You two are to be cast out at sunrise.
Sorry, but Stoors must come first.
Truth is, he was in your place...
Sadoc likely would've
done the same thing.
Sadoc?
Our trail-finder. He
was called Sadoc Burrows.
Sadoc Burrows was your leader's name?
Just so's we're both working with
a full bushel, I don't believe you.
I'm only showin' you this
to make good and sure.
Sure of what?
Story goes, in ancient
days, there was a Stoor.
Wasn't like the rest of us.
They say he dreamed
one night of a place,
with endless streams of cold water
and rollin' hills so soft,
a family could dig a hole
and live in it in less than a month.
He called it "the Sûzat."
Struck out one year with a
caravan of followers to find it.
Promised, when he did,
he'd send someone back
to gather the rest of us.
But that was the last any of us
ever heard of Rorimas Burrows.
Poppy's walkin' song.
Harfoots have been here before.
Your kind's home, where you come from,
does it look like this?
Have you come back here to
lead us all to the Sûzat?
I think, um...
Rorimas never found the Sûzat.
And after a while...
we just kept wanderin'.
We don't have a home.
The riders sighted. Big
folk. Comin' this way.
To what do we owe the pleasure of...
The Harfoots, where are they?
The only halflings we know
about in this desert are Stoors.
Do you know why we wear these masks?
Defy the Dark Wizard and,
when we return with him,
you will find out for yourselves.
I know you believe this
Ring is deceiving me.
But I believe it is guiding me,
and that following it may
be our only path to victory.
Is there no point at which the
cost of victory becomes too great?
I have yet to reach that point.
How does that not terrify you?
Because the suffering of
a world ruled by Sauron
terrifies me more.
I have always felt it. But
with this Ring, I can see it.
Everything we stand to lose if
we fail in the task before us.
My father foresaw that, one day,
Celebrimbor's life would be in my hands.
I will choose the path I must to give me
the best hope of protecting it.
Protecting that which is most fragile,
most dear, is a task
entrusted to all Elves.
And one that is not yet complete.
And I promise you, there will
be more painful sacrifices.
Galadriel?
Promise me, Elrond,
you will put opposing Sauron
above all other considerations.
Even my life.
I will make no promise whose
asking is borne of that Ring.
But I swear to you...
defeating Sauron will come first.
Even before you.
Forgive me, commander, we heard drums.
Is that the key to the manacles?
Believe he meant for you to
decide whether or not to use it.
I'm sorry.
So am I.
No. Isildur, y'see...
Forgiveness doesn't
come to folk like me.
Sooner or later, they'll cast
me out, you know they will.
I won't let them.
I won't let them cast you out.
Put down the sword.
Estrid, drop the sword!
Estrid!
Stop!
I am Arondir, of the Greenwood.
Hast thou ever touched
axe to wooded life?
To my great pain, I have, but...
Listen to me!
It is not for felling trees.
What does it fell?
Orcs.
Stay back.
There was an...
an army of them.
Maiming and murdering as they marched.
We saw what they did.
Is that why you're here?
Why you're so angry?
The spilling sap and burning
branch called to us from afar.
But... we were too late.
An army? How long ago was this?
Winterbloom nourished many of
those trees from seed and sprout.
Do not ask her to speak more of it.
They are no different from them!
Disemboweling, and uprooting,
branch-breakers and trunk-splitters, all!
We would seek...
your forgiveness...
for the injury...
... we have done.
Forgiveness takes an age.
Rain washing clear the
long memory of soil.
New bark, covering old scars.
And in all that time, I promise,
we will see to it that the trees
of this wood are left in peace.
Think they know what peace is?
It is what comes after the night storms,
when the dawn is silent,
and the birds awaken.
We have tended this forest
since before the mountains
rose up and divided it.
When the only sound here was
the light upon the moss...
Theo?
And the breathing of the leaves.
Yes. We know peace.
Estrid? It's me.
Estrid? Estrid.
Hagen?
- What... I thought you...
- So did I.
I can't believe you're
here. Look at you.
Thank you for coming for me.
I made a promise.
Thank you for keepin' it.
Now I must keep another.
Orcs are on the move. I must
follow the trail where it leads.
Perhaps have another
chance to confront Adar.
You can come with me, if you wish.
I have promises of my own to keep.
Then mae glenno. Lord of Pelargir.
Orc-treachery.
That trail.
I gather it leads to...
Eregion, my liege.
We came in search of Sauron.
And instead, we find Adar?
Could they be in league
with each other or...
Perhaps at war.
A legion of Orcs have
marched into Elvish lands.
We are all of us at war.
Word of this must reach the High
King before our host sails for Mordor.
There!
Hold!
But that's our supper gettin' away!
Come on!
Back in line!
Who is it? Keep looking.
They're nearby. Keep lookin'.
Who is it? What was that?
Came from over here.
I can smell an Elf.
Amazing.
Leave no stone unturned. Go!
Get to Lindon. I will occupy
them as long as I am able.
Keep looking.
Take it.
Take it, Elrond.
Over there.
Where's the rest?
I stand alone.
Cut off her right thumb.
Tell us where the others are,
I'll let you keep the left.
She sacrificed herself to save us all.
No, you are mistaken, Camnir.
She did not do it to save us.
What?
She did it to save the ring.
Hurry.
These are Elven lands.
Go back to the shadow.
A star shines on the
hour of our meeting...
Lady Galadriel.
♪ Now let the song begin ♪
♪ Let us sing together ♪
♪ Of sun, stars, moon and mist, ♪
♪ Rain and cloudy weather ♪
♪ Light on the budding leaf ♪
♪ Dew on the feather ♪
♪ Wind on the open hill ♪
♪ Bells on the heather ♪
♪ O slender as a willow-wand ♪
♪ O clearer than clear water ♪
♪ O reed by the living pool ♪
♪ Fair River-daughter ♪
♪ O springtime and summertime ♪
♪ And spring again after ♪
♪ O wind on the waterfall ♪
♪ And the leaves' laughter ♪
♪ Old Tom Bombadil ♪
♪ Is a merry fellow ♪
♪ Bright blue his jacket is ♪
♪ And his boots are yellow ♪
♪ Reeds by the shady pool ♪
♪ Lilies on the water ♪
♪ Old Tom Bombadil ♪
♪ And the River-daughter ♪
♪ O slender as a willow-wand ♪
♪ O clearer than clear water ♪
♪ O reed by the living pool ♪
♪ Fair River-daughter ♪
♪ O springtime and summertime ♪
♪ And spring again after ♪
♪ O wind on the waterfall ♪
♪ And the leaves' laughter ♪
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -